Jude Furtal. Jarvis Consulting

Recent engineering master s graduate from the Lassonde School of Engineering at York University who is curious, adaptable, enjoys learning, and excels in collaborating with others. Excellent knowledge of the software development cycle, object-oriented programming, and data structures & algorithms. Along with experience in Information Technology (IT), Agile/Scrum and backend development can be utilized for a Data Engineer position. Excited to learn and work on projects related to Data Engineering such as database management, desktop/web applications, server cluster monitoring systems and many more. Additional skills and hobbies include, public speaking, writing documentations, multi-tasking, creating artwork, and planning fun social events for communities.

Skills

Proficient: Java, Linux/Bash, RDBMS/SQL, Agile/Scrum, Git, GitHub, GitFlow, Data Structures & Algorithms

Competent: Docker, JDBC, REST APIs, Mockito, Spring Framework, SpringBoot, Apache MAVEN

Familiar: Java Script, HTML, Security/Encryption, Character Encoding, Virtual Machines

Development Projects

Project source code: https://github.com/jarviscanada/jarvis_data_eng_JudeFurtal

- Cluster Monitor: Implemented a Linux Cluster Monitoring tool to monitor cluster resources and usage. The tool is designed to operate on an arbitrary number of nodes/servers in a network and was developed using Bash, Docker, RDBMS, and SQL.
- Core Java Apps: Created three Core Java Applications that represent the foundation of data engineering. These applications highlight features such as lambdas/streams, regular expressions, JDBC, REST APIs, DAO, and Spring design patterns.
- SpringBoot App: In-progressCloud & DevOps: Not started
- Hadoop: Not started Spark/Scala: Not started

Professional Experiences

Software Developer, Jarvis, Toronto (2020-Present): Implemented various software applications using numerous development tools such as Java, Bash, SQL etc. Teamwork and communication skills were demonstrated when working with members in a Scrum team.

Teaching Assistant, York University, Toronto (2017-2019): Facilitated labs and tutorials for undergraduate engineering students. Public speaking skills were utilized when speaking to classes of over 30 students. Time management skills were used when grading assignments/tests and having them returned to students promptly.

Summer Student, Canadian Automobile Association, Thornhill (2016): Worked in the Information Technology (IT) department. Was responsible for installing a batch job scheduling software (BMC Control-M) into the IT environment. Then trained the IT staff on how to operate the new scheduling software.

Education & Academic Projects

York University (2017-2020), Master of Applied Science, Mechanical Engineering

- **DESCENT Satellite Project:** Worked in a diverse team from design to implementation of two satellites for the DESCENT space mission. Developed software using the C programming language to measure the deployment length of the Electrodynamic Tether used for DESCENT.
- ESSENCE Satellite Project: Assigned one of the team lead positions for the ESSENCE space mission. Project management and leadership skills were utilized when leading and supporting all the undergraduate students working on the team.

York University (2012-2017), Bachelor of Engineering, Space Engineering

- Satellite Tracking Software: Implemented a software application in Java to track high altitude satellites. The software reads positional data for a satellite in an Earth-centric coordinate system and then converts the positional information into a topocentric coordinate system used by ground station antennas.
- Solar Panels Efficiency Test: Developed software in C to use an Arduino microcontroller to measure the efficiency of different solar panels. The software would record the voltage output from each set of solar panels and the results were then displayed to the screen.

Certificates & Awards & Activities

• Best Presenter Award, York University (2019): Gave the best presentation at the York Research Seminar